leapcard.ie 2013-09-30

# Privacy Statement and Use of Cookies

## General Statement

  1. Leapcard.ie is owned by the National Transport Authority (the “Authority”). This statement relates to the privacy practices of the Authority in connection with this website. Any external links to other websites are clearly identifiable as such. Some technical terms used in this statement are explained at the end of this page. 

The Authority fully respects your right to privacy, and will not collect any personal information about you on this website without your clear permission. Any personal information which you volunteer to the Authority will be treated strictly in accordance with the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003. 

##  Use of Cookies on LeapCard.ie

## What are Cookies?

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer when you visit a website, including by leapcard.ie. Leapcard.ie uses cookies for several purposes, including to remember which pages on this website have already been visited and to enable the site to remember if you’re already logged in to your online account or have added an item to your shopping cart. You can find more details about cookies here: [www.cookiecentral.com/faq/](http://www.cookiecentral.com/faq/)

By continuing to use Leapcard.ie you are agreeing to our use of cookies as described on this page. 

## Cookies used by LeapCard.ie

LeapCard.ie uses 5 types of cookies

  * 1.A “Session ID” cookie
  * 2.An “Analytics” cookie
  * 3.A “login” cookie
  * 4.A shopping basket cookie
  * 5.A “surveys” cookie

Note that Leapcard.ie does not use third party “tracking” cookies.

COOKIE | COOKIE NAME | PURPOSE  
---|---|---  
**Session ID Cookie** | ASP.Net_SessionId  | This cookie is created automatically by the websites’ server software (Microsoft IIS). This cookie is generated when first visiting the site and is used to information necessary for the website to operate correctly.

For more information, visit: <http://support.microsoft.com/kb/899918>  
  
**Analytics Cookie** | .ASPXANONYMOUS | This cookie is created automatically by the websites' server software (Microsoft IIS). This cookie is generated when first visiting the site and is used to record what pages you visit, and is killed when you finish browsing. This cookie does not contain any information that would identify the user.

For more information, refer to the section below entitled “Collection And Use Of Technical Information”  
  
**Login cookie** | .ASPXFORMSAUTH | When you login to your account on Leapcard.ie we generate a cookie that helps the website to remember this information and allowing you to navigate from page to page without having to enter your login details each time you click on a link. Without this cookie, you will not be able to use the “Your Account” area of the website. This cookie is automatically deleted when you logout.  
**Shopping Basket Cookie** | ShBCookie | This cookie is used to remember the contents of your Shopping Basket. It contains only a reference to the database table identifier in the web database, and does not contain any user identifying information. Without this cookie, you will not be able to use the shopping basket functionality in the website. This cookie will last for 24 hours.  
**Surveys cookie** | Varies | Contains only a reference to the database table identifier in the web database, it does not contain user information.

This cookie only lasts for the current user session   
  
## Can I delete these Cookies?

Yes. Most internet browsers have a menu option that you can select to delete cookies. If you are not sure how to do this you can check your help options or search on the internet for the instructions specific to your browser software. There are also software applications available that can do this for you automatically. However, please note that every time you subsequently visit Leapcard.ie we will place a new cookie on your computer.

## What if I want to disable Cookies?

If you would like to disable cookies, you can turn off the use of cookies in your internet browser settings. You may also have the option to choose to be notified when a website attempts to place a cookie on your computer. If you are not sure how to do this you can check your help options or search on the internet for the instructions specific to your browser software. 

**WARNING** \- disabling cookie support will prevent Leapcard.ie from functioning properly and you will not be able to utilise fully all of its features and information. 

## Collection and Use of Personal Information

The Authority does not collect any personal data about you on this website, apart from information which you volunteer (for example by contacting us, buying or topping-up a Leap Card online or subscribing to the Leapcard.ie newsletters through this website).   
By signing up for an online account when purchasing a Leap Card/travel credit and/or by registering your Leap Card account, you agree to and acknowledge that the Authority may use the personal data provided in line with the purpose for which it is provided, including the following purposes:   

  * 1.as is necessary to issue the Leap Card;
  * 2.as is necessary for the purposes of processing your transaction and/or managing your Leap Card account;
  * 3.as is necessary for the performance of the Leap Card Terms and Conditions; 
  * 4.as is necessary to log card usage data; 
  * 5.as is necessary to provide customer support; and 
  * 6.the provision of Authority and Leap Card Service Provider information and information relating thereto.
  * 7.Leap Card customers will also have the option to subscribe to Leapcard.ie newsletters, which may include offers from Service Providers and trusted third parties.

If you choose not to sign up for an online account when purchasing or topping-up a Leap Card or do not opt-in to subscribe to the Leapcard.ie newsletter then the Authority will use the personal data you provide solely for the purposes of processing your transaction and/or managing your Leap Card account. 

The information you provide to the Authority may occasionally be passed to third parties located outside the European Economic Area solely for the purposes of the operation of the integrated ticketing scheme (and not for direct marketing purposes). The Authority will always take steps to ensure adequate contractual and technical safeguards are in place to protect personal data and that such third parties only use personal data in accordance with the Authority’s instructions, this privacy statement and all applicable laws. 

At no time will information provided by you be disclosed to any third parties (other than as set out in the Leap Card Terms and Conditions) unless in accordance with the law. Your personal data may be made anonymous and used for statistical purposes. 

You may choose unsubscribe from our newsletter at any time by clicking here or emailing [customer.care@leapcard.ie](mailto:customer.care@leapcard.ie). If you opted in to receive Leapcard.ie newsletters you may choose to unsubscribe by logging in to your online account or emailing [customer.care@leapcard.ie](mailto:customer.care@leapcard.ie). 

You may also choose to provide us with personal data (e.g. name, e-mail and postal address) in correspondence to one of the addresses listed on our website. We use these details solely for the purpose of dealing with your query. 

## Your Rights Regarding Data Supplied Via This Website

  1. You have a right to be given a copy of your personal data which you may have supplied to the Authority. To exercise this right, you must send a letter to PO Box 12119, Dublin 24 or e-mail [customer.care@leapcard.ie](mailto:%20customer.care@leapcard.ie). You should include any personal identifiers which you supplied earlier via the website (e.g. Name; address; phone number; e-mail). Your request will be dealt with within forty days. 

You also have a right to have inaccurate information corrected. If you discover that there is inaccurate personal information on your online account you can amend it by signing in and making the appropriate edits. If you discover that this office holds other inaccurate information about you, you have a right to instruct the Authority to correct that information. Such an instruction must be in writing or via e-mail. Your request will be dealt with within forty days. 

The Authority will not hold your personal data for longer than necessary. In certain circumstances you may also request that data which you have supplied via the website be deleted. To exercise this right you would generally be expected to identify some contravention of data protection law in the manner in which this office processes the data concerned. We will endeavour to comply with such requests, subject to your agreeing to waive any right to dispute previous transactions to which the data to be deleted may relate. 

## Complaints About Data Processed Via The Website

  1. If you are concerned about how personal data is processed via this website, please do not hesitate to bring such concerns to the attention of the Authority. 

## Links to other websites

This website may provide links to third-party web sites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave this web site. The Authority is not responsible for the content of external internet sites.

## Collection And Use Of Technical Information

  1. Technical details in connection with visits to this website are logged by our internet service provider for our statistical purposes. The technical details logged include the following items: 

  * The IP address of the visitor’s web server;
  * The top-level domain name used (for example .ie, .com, .org, .net); 
  * The previous website address from which the visitor reached us, including any search terms used; 
  * Click-stream data which shows the traffic of visitors around this web site (for example pages accessed and documents downloaded);
  * Type of web browser used by the website visitor.

  1. It is the policy of the Authority never to disclose such technical information in respect of individual website visitors to any third party (apart from our internet service provider, which records such data on our behalf and which is bound by confidentiality provisions in this regard), unless obliged to disclose such information by a rule of law. The technical information will be used only by the Authority, and only for statistical and other administrative purposes. You should note that technical details, which we cannot associate with any identifiable individual, do not constitute "personal data" for the purposes of the Data Protection Acts, 1988 & 2003\. 

## Glossary Of Technical Terms Used

  1. Web Browser \- The piece of software you use to read web pages. Examples are Microsoft Internet Explorer, Google Chrome, Firefox and Opera. 

  1. IP Address \- The identifying details for your computer (or your internet company’s computer), expressed in "internet protocol" code (for example 192.168.72.34). Every computer connected to the web has a unique IP address, although the address may not be the same every time a connection is made. 

  1. Cookies \- Small pieces of information, stored in files, placed on your computer by a web site. Cookies can be read by the web site on your subsequent visits. 

_Last updated September 2012_
